Shrikant Ram

Lead Software Engineer Location: Kolkata, India



+91 9625464616, 9711692431 <u>Shri0402@gmail.com</u>, <u>shri0402@yahoo.com</u> www.linkedin.com/in/shrikant0402

Web developer with 8+ years of rich experience in software development and diverse experience working on multiple **Angular** Application. Good understanding of enterprise Web Architecture and different type of Enterprise Application Platform (SDLC). Also, I have experience in using different software development methodologies like scrum, Agile and waterfall. I have sound knowledge of UI Architecture micro front-end. Skilled in Angular, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Express.js, CSS, SASS, SCSS, Limitless framework, GIT, Node.js, Material, Kendo, PrimNg UI kit.

Skills:

NPM – 5.5Yrs Material, Kendo, Prime-Ng – 5.5Yrs Git/Bitbucket – 5.5Yrs

Experience:



Lead Software Engineer

Capgemini · Full-time (Sep 2021 - Present) · 2 yrs. 10 mos.

Kolkata, West Bengal, India · On-site

Project: Covestro, Baker Hughes, HMH, Trevish-Methew, Amgen



User Interface Consultant

Infogain. Full-time (Jan 2020 - Aug 2021) \cdot 1 yrs. 8 mos.

Noida Area, India

Projects: Oracle Smart Search, FMCO



Senior Frontend Developer

ClixLogix. Full-time (Oct 2017 - Jan 2020) · 2 yrs. 4 mos.

Noida sector 65

Projects: Veriklick, Hope-JAX, Humanbase, Real Estate buzz, HappyHR, Suvari



Junior Software Developer

Shaurya Software Pvt. Ltd. Full-time (Aug 2014 - Oct 2016) · 2 yrs. 3 mos.

New Delhi Area, India

Project: Stufee, School ERP

Projects: (some of the current project mentioned below)

Covestro (Germany: Offsite) – Feb 2024 to Present (Full Time) https://www.covestro.com

Covestro is a Germany based company. Who is providing several equipment. Working on one of the projects where machine engineer can show all data of running machine with the help of Covestro application.

Technology: Angular, JavaScript, SAAS, HTML, SCSS, JIRA, GIT, Java

Backer Hughes (Kolkata: Offsite) - Jan 2022 to March 2023 (Full Time) https://www.bakerhughes.com/

Oil and Energy domain related project. Application for monitoring pressure and all real time measurement of running oil digging machine.

Technology: Angular, SAAS, MySQL, Express.JS, HTML, CSS, Jesmin-Karma, Azure DevOps

First MCO FMCO (Noida: Offsite) - Oct 2020 to Aug 2021 (Full Time) https://www.firstmco.com/

It is a SPA Management Application. Help to Hospital admin management team to Store the entire information of a patient with all phases of treatment and hospitality.

Technology: Angular, SAAS, Node.js, Express.JS, HTML, CSS

Smart Search UI Confidential (Noida: Offsite) - Mar 2020 to Sep 2020 (Full Time)

It is a Web application which developed for user search a quarry and shows the list of solution, and users can be resolved hardware-related solutions with one click.

Technology: Angular, SAAS, MySQL, Express.JS, HTML, CSS,

Qualification:



B-Tech (Computer Science & Engg.) 2009-2013 - 70% GDPA



Higher Education (Science) 2007-2009 - 60%



Basic Education 2007-71%

Training / courses:

Azure DevOps - March 27, 2023 Front-end Framework React – July 27, 2023 Intro to ChatGPT and Generative AI – Feb 27, 2024 Scaled Agile Software Development & SDLC(SAFe) – Feb 24, 2023 Server-Side Development with Node.js, Express, Mongo DB – Oct 17, 2022 Front-end Web UI Frameworks and Tools - Nov 19, 2022

Languages:

English:

Hindi:

Bengali: ★★★☆☆

Date:

Place: Kolkata